on behalf of the Prudential Sean's
company it is my very pleasant duty to
welcome you here today the face of
prudence an iconic image known by
millions around the world and
representing our company
a company with over a hundred and
sixty-five years of history our powerful
brand is well known and highly regarded
we've come a long way
but to really understand the present we
must first understand our past
18:48 industrialization is sweeping
across Europe bringing both uncertainty
and opportunity for all classes there's
a demand for better workers rights
people are looking for a sense of
security and in this year on the 30th of
May a group of Victorian gentlemen
respond to these turbulent times by
forming the Prudential mutual Assurance
investment and Loan Association its aim
to in fix habits of prudence among many
individuals to represent the values of
the business the figure of prudence is
adopted as the symbol of the company to
this day she still carries her aro
signifying strength of purpose serpent
the ancient symbol of wisdom and mirror
representing self-awareness
[Music]
18:54 the company widens its reach by
opening its industrial branch
introducing a new concept
penny policies for the industrial
working class population to build the
business the company introduces a new
breed of salesmen who travel
door-to-door armed with statistics and
tables the men from the Peru
and with this new market sales grow
dramatically 1871 the company is the
first in the City of London to employ
women as Clark's through the 1870s the
company grows considerably in 1873 there
are 47 agents by 1888 there are 10,000
609 by 1879 the company has outgrown its
premises at Lud gate Hill and moves into
the striking purpose-built Hogan bars
headquarters by 1898 Prudential has
become the number one life company in
the United Kingdom with almost 30
million pounds in accumulated funds it's
now at the heart of everyday life nearly
one in three households has a policy
with the Peru
April 14th 1912 SS Titanic sinks on its
maiden voyage
Prudential promptly pays out claims on
292 passengers hardly any disaster could
occur without Prudential in some way
providing security to the deprived and
bereft
[Music]
by the end of the First World War
Prudential has paid claims representing
almost 1/3 of the British soldiers
killed in 1919 Prudential offers general
insurance for the first time which
enables the company to start an
extraordinary international expansion
in India in 1923 the first overseas life
branch is established with the first
policy being sold to a tea planter in
Assam the business soon covered the
whole of the subcontinent with offices
in Bombay Calcutta salon and Delhi in
1924 Prudential expands to Malaysia and
by 1931 a branch is established in
raffles Square Singapore by 1939
Prudential's overseas business is
rivaling the success of its UK
operations by the end of the Second
World War
Prudential has paid five and a half
million pounds in claims on nearly a
hundred and ten thousand deaths 1949 the
famous man from the Peru advertising
campaign is launched 1967 twelve million
people watch the first-ever Prudential
commercials on British television the
man from the Peru is truly established
as a household name talk it over with
the man from the provincial throughout
the 70s and 80s prudential continues to
grow and respond to customers changing
needs in 1986 prudential gains a firm
foothold in the united states the
world's largest life insurance and
retirement savings market with the
acquisition of jackson national life
insurance company with 78 million baby
boomers reaching retirement over the
next 20 years
Jackson is well-placed to help them meet
their needs for retirement income 1994
is a milestone year as Prudential
recognizing the high potential for
growth and expansion across Asia
establishes Prudential Corporation Asia
the regional head office in Hong Kong
sets out to expand operations beyond
Malaysia Singapore and Hong Kong
businesses are soon established in
Indonesia Thailand Vietnam and the
Philippines in the UK at 1999 Prudential
strengthens the group's investment
management opportunities with the
acquisition of fund managers M&G
engi itself has a long history of
innovation in 1931 the company launched
the first ever unit trust in the United
Kingdom over the next 12 years
Prudential is to become the leading
international life insurer in Asia
expanding into 13 markets and meeting
the savings and protection needs of a
fast growing middle class across the
region Prudential has established strong
distribution channels including
partnerships with banks across the
region and an extensive network of
trained agents 2012 credentials Asia
asset management business one of the
leading fund managers in the region is
rebranded as East spring investments
paving the way for its expansion into
the u.s. in the same year in the United
Kingdom Prudential is a leading life and
Pensions provider to around 7 million
customers with a focus on pensions
saving and investments Prudential now
has around 24 million insurance
customers over 26,000 employees more
than 400,000 agents in Asia for stock
exchange listings in London Hong Kong
New York and Singapore and more than 400
billion pounds of assets under
management we've come a long way not
only with the expansion of our business
but also our work in giving back to the
communities we live and work in today
Prudential is a company with a broader
scope a wider geographic spread and
greater investment power than could ever
have been imagined in 1848 but our
founding principles of integrity
security and prudence
still guide us in promoting long-term
financial security for our customers and
building social and economic value in
our communities around the world
you